So, to calculate your growth metrics,
要计算你的发展指标
you would actually get the data from your data team.
可从你的数据团队处获取相关数据
So, for daily active users,
日活跃用户统计的是
this would be the number of users who were active in the particular 24-hour time window,
在特定的 24 小时内活跃的用户数量
and the particular 24-hour time window is defined by the date you give the data team.
而特定的 24 小时是你要给数据团队指定的日期
For monthly active users,
月活跃用户统计的是
that would be the number of users who were active within the month-long time window.
在一个月内活跃的用户数量
So, let's assume for our mock data we have here,
看看我们的模拟数据
we have the daily active users provided based on the last day of each month,
日活跃用户基于每个月最后一天的数据
and the monthly active users is building off of that.
月活跃用户的数据也是如此
So, for the whole month,
整个月里
give us the number of users who were active.
活跃的用户数量是这些
I created the bar graphs here to depict the numbers we had up here,
我建了条形图来呈现这些数据
and you can see that there is a dip in the number of
与 9 月 30 日相比 10 月 30 日的活跃用户数量
active users on October 30th compared to September 30th,
明显下降了
but it steadily improves after that.
但之后又稳步上升了
But the monthly active users count,
而月活跃用户人数
which is the number of users who were active in the last month, were steadily increasing.
统计的是上一个月的活跃用户人数 这些数据稳步上升
A better interpretation of the DAU and monthly
要更好地解释日活跃用户和月活跃用户指标
active user metric is using the stickiness ratio.
就要利用用户黏度
So, let's go ahead and calculate the stickiness.
让我们计算一下用户黏度
I'm using the formula provided here,
要用到这一个公式
and I'm using it for all of the months.
计算这些月份的用户黏度
So, this would be daily active users over monthly active users,
首先 将日活跃用户除以月活跃用户
and I have a graph that I will go over in a minute.
稍后再讲解统计图
So now, we have the stickiness ratio calculated here.
这里已经算出用户黏度
A stickiness ratio of one means that every user who visited the website in
如果用户黏度为 1 则表示
the last month was also active on
上个月的网站访客
the day on which the daily active user account was generated.
在生成日活跃用户数据的那一天也表现活跃
You can see here that our stickiness ratio range between 0.1 to 0.21.
这里我们的用户黏度处于 0.1 到 0.21 之间
This is the proportion of monthly active users who
这是在特定的 24 小时内
came back to your product in that 24-hour or day window.
使用了你的产品的月活跃用户的比例
So, 0.2 ratio means 20 percent of the month.
比率 0.2 表示这个月有 20% 天数
So six days out of the last month,
也就是上个月有六天
the user was back online looking at the website or app.
用户再次到上线浏览网站或应用程序
If you're ratio is say 0.01,
如果比率为 0.01
that's less than a day,
那就是不到一天
and that's a problem scenario.
这种情况就有问题了
So, engagement metrics are useful metrics to gauge how
因此 参与度指标可以用来衡量
often your website is being used and a good guide for your business.
你的网站的使用频率 这对你的业务规划有帮助
This line chart is a visualization tool
折线图是一种视觉化工具
business analysts use to show the stickiness ratio.
业务分析师用此来呈现用户黏度比率
It can be used to show email campaigns or
如果新推出一些网站功能
experiments when your website features were introduced.
就可以用折线图来显示电子邮件营销或者功能试用情况
They coincide with high or low stickiness ratio and
可以反映出高或低的用户黏度比率
can help guide future plans to introduce or revisit specific effort.
有助于计划未来应该推出或修改的内容